Russia, Moscow,

Telephone: +7 (985) 765-55-38 (cell) Email: Khapov.Igor@gmail.com

Khapov.Igor@ru.ibm.com

Khapov Igor

Head of virtualization development department (IBM Science and Technology center)

Summary of qualification:

Team manager and technical expert with more than 15 years of development experience. Blockchain evangelist. Docker and Kubernetes expert. Lead development Data Science Experience Local on Power with GPU support. Filed patent "Portable Dynamic Binary Translated Multi-Architecture Container Images".

Cloud advisor. Lead workload transformation analysis project from idea to production as a manager, technical lead and developer. Patent in the cloud migration area.

Speaker on multiple local and international conferences (Blockchain, Docker, Kubernetes, development). Mentor and participant in multiple hackatons. Teacher for the German development lab and IBM clients. Technical expert for many local client engagements.

Expert in DevOps area. Lead DevOps stream in bank audit project. Ability to develop DevOps process from scratch.

People and project manager with more than 5 years experience. High level of PM skills and experience to work as technical lead of the project. MBA with project management focus.

Skills

- ✓ DevOps
- ✓ Cloud API: OpenStack API, SoftLayer API, AWS
- ✓ Containers: Docker, kubernetes, IBM Cloud private, OpenShift, OpenWhisk
- ✓ Programming Languages: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, shell scripting, TCL/TK
- ✓ Automation: Ansible, UCD, Jenkins
- ✓ Version control/IDE: git, Subversion, CVS, Eclipse/Rational
- ✓ DB: SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL), NoSQL (MongoDB, CouchDB, Redis)
- ✓ OS: Linux, Windows Server, OS

Experience

December 2005 — November 2007 Job title: Technician Speciality: CAD system development November 2007 — here and now Job title: Engineer Speciality: CAD system development	VSUE - All-Russia Research Institute of Automatics (VNIIA). Russian federal atomic energy agency		
February 2008 — June 2008 Speciality: Developer	freelancer Development Fund of Economic and Financial Research "Finance and Development"		
February 2010 — June 2010 Speciality: Developer	freelancer Organization closed session		
2011 — 2012 Job title: Volunteer developer	Big Change Charity foundation		
February 2010 — February 2013 Job title: Software Engineer	IBM Science and Technology Ce	nter	
February 2013 — August 2015 Job title: Lead developer	IBM Science and Technology Center		
August 2015 — here and now Job title: Head of virtualization development department	IBM Science and Technology Center		
Education			
September 2002 — February 2008 Speciality: «Automated information processing and management»	Moscow State Institute of Radio-Engineering, Electronics and Automation (Technical University), Moscow, Russia		
September 2007 — June 2010 Speciality: «Translator in the professional communications area (English)»	Teaching foreign languages center (TFLC)		
September 2012 — June 2014 «MBA with PM speciality»	The Russian Presidential Academy of National Economy and Public Administration (RANEPA)		
Qualification improvement			
November 2006 — March 2007 Speciality: «Programming in C /C++» March 2009 — April 2009 Qualification: «New information technology» March 2009 — April 2009 Speciality: «Programming in Java»	Computer Training Center "Spetsialist.RU" at the Bauman Moscow State Technical University		
January 2008 Speciality: «Public speech»	Russian federal atomic energy agency		
May 2019 – Kubernetes administrator	Linux Foundation		